Abdul Rahim

- GCP DevOPs Engineer
- Pangalore, India

EDUCATION

- Electronics & Communication Engineering
- JNTU Anantapur
- 2008 2012

Technical Skills

- Cloud: GCP, AWS
- Version Control: GIT/ Bit-Bucket
- Linux Administration
- CI/CD: Jenkins,
 Cloudbuid, Codefresh
- · Micro services: Docker
- Terraform Infra as a Code
- Kubernetes (GKE)
 Administration
- Middleware (WebSphere/JBOSS)
- WebSphere Commerce Server
- Monitoring:
 Prometheus, Grafana,
 Kiali, Jaeger tracing,
 Stackdriver, Dynatrace
- Agile Methodologies
- Twistlock Security Suite
- Jira, ServiceNow, Maximo
- Checkmarx SAST
- Istio Service Mesh
- Pipeline Automation
- GCP Serverless



vsabdulrahim@gmail.com

+91 9916246912

PROFILE

A Cloud enthusiastic team player having around 9+ years of Experience in IT industry as a DevOps Engineer in architecting, supporting, automating, and optimizing mission critical deployments over large infrastructure. Proficient with Cloud Computing, Source code management and in developing CI/CD pipelines, DevOps processes, Agile Methodology and Application administration.

EXPERIENCE

· Solution Designer - GCP

HCL Tech Feb 2021 to Till date

DevOps Engineer

Devon Software Services Pvt Ltd Oct 2018 to Jan 2021

Infrastructure Specialist

IBM India Pvt Ltd Feb 2016 to Oct 2018

· Middleware Administrator

IBM India Pvt Ltd - Contractor May 2013 to Feb 2016

CERTIFICATIONS



• Certified Kubernetes Administrator (CKA)



AWS Solution Architect Certified – Expired



GCP Certified Professional



 IBM Certified System Administrator -WebSphere Application Server Network Deployment V8.5

Projects

ANZ Bank, Australia

- Role: Solution Designer - GCP
- Environment : Google Cloud, Docker, GKE, Terraform, Istio Service Mesh
- CI/CD Tools : Jenkins, CloudBuild, Codefresh, Git, Bitbucket, JFrog,
- OS: Linux
- Languages. : Bash,
 Shell scripting
- Monitoring tools: Stack Driver, Prometheus, Grafana, Kiali, Jaeger Tracing

Kramp B2B, Netherlands

- · Role: DevOps Engineer
- Environment : Google Cloud, GKE, WebSphere Application Server 7.X, Apache Solr Search,
- WebSphere App Server, WebSphere Commerce Server
- CI/CD Tools : Jenkins, CloudBuild, SVN, Bitbucket, JFrog, Maven
- OS: AIX, Linux
- Monitoring tools:
 Dynatrace, Stack Driver,

- Worked on google cloud platform (GCP) services like GKE, Compute Engine, IAM, GCS, Pub Sub, , Stack-Driver, Monitoring, VPC, Load Balancing.
- Developed strategy for cloud migration and implementation of best practices using GCP services
- Delivering Proof of Concepts for new Solutions on Google Cloud
- Implementing the DevSecOps processes that integrates security as part of CI/CD lifecycle
- Developed and implemented automated CI/CD pipelines for code deployments using Codefresh, CloudBuild.
- Integration of SAST and Twistlock Security Suites as part of CI/CD.
- Build and deployed Docker, improving developer workflow, increasing scalability, and optimizing speed.
- Manage Cloud infrastructure services and IAM permissions.
- Managing Istio Service Mesh to Secure service-to-service communication encryption, Automatic load balancing for HTTP, gRPC, WebSocket, and TCP traffic
- Maintained Git workflows for version controls (GIT, JFROG).
- · Bash shell-scripts to automate routine activities.
- Developed Terraform Scripts and modules to create, configure, and manage cloud infrastructure for host projects and service projects.
- Setup GCP Firewall rules to allow or deny traffic to and from the VM's instances based on specified configuration
- Working with engineering and upstream teams on day-today environment issues on DEV and TEST env.
- Point team player on Kubernetes for creating new Projects, Services for load balancing and adding them to Routes to be accessible from outside, Creation of Pods through new application and control the scaling of pods, troubleshooting
- Provide thought leadership as organization migrates to modern development practices
- Application monitoring using Google Stackdriver, Prometheus, Grafana
- Istio Service Mesh Monitoring using Kiali, Jaeger tracing
- Hands on experience on Google Cloud Platform services like GKE, Compute Engine, Cloud Functions, Cloud Run, Cloud KMS, IAM, Datastore, Storage, Pub Sub, Dataflow, Stack-Driver, Monitoring, VPC, Load Balancing.
- · Hands-on experience setting up Kubernetes (k8s) Clusters for running microservices, implementing autoscaling, Kubernetes services (ClusterIP, NodePort, Ingress), Troubleshooting and administration of Kubernetes (GKE) cluster of various environments.
 - Developed and maintained automated CI/CD pipelines for code deployments using Jenkins, CloudBuild.
 - Build and deployed Docker containers to break up monolithic app into microservices, improving developer workflow, increasing scalability, and optimizing speed.
 - Manage Cloud infrastructure services and IAM permissions.
 - Set-up databases in GCP using Redis, datastore, and create storage buckets with fine grained access control.
 - Create Disks, Volumes, and scripts to take snapshots of volumes.

Maintaining secrets as part of cloudbuild pipelines and secret manager

- Implemented Cloud-Schedulers and K8s Cron-Jobs to run daily sync jobs for multiple services
- Deploying and managing serverless function Cloud-Run and Cloud-Function
- Provide the permissions and required access to all the pub/sub topics
- Setup Alerting and monitoring using Stackdriver in GCP.
- Create custom log metrics using Stackdriver logging and create charts and alerts using the custom log metrics.
- Maintained Git workflows for version controls (Bitbucket, SVN)
- Bash shell-scripts to automate routine activities.
- Administering Linux/AIX systems and server infrastructure/ architecture
- Working with the Agile development team
- Worked with Product Owners/Release Managers and development teams to support Build/Release Management.
- Developed Ansible, Terraform Scripts and modules to create, configure, and manage cloud infrastructure.
- Monitoring, troubleshooting and issue resolution for relevant web applications and database servers.
- Operational experience deploying and maintaining highavailability web applications and services.
- · Monitored serves, application performance Linux scripts regularly.
- Provided support by 24×7 shift rotation basis.

Installation and Configuration of WebSphere Application Server Installation Server

- Installed IHS Server on different nodes and configured them by generating the plug-in.
- Experienced in Setting up of Nodes, Data Sources, including planning installation and configuration of WebSphere Application Server.
- Created multiple Profiles on WebSphere Application server 7.x.8.x
- Hands on experience in deployment of J2EE applications on WebSphere Application Servers 7.x.8.x
- Involved in Configuring WebSphere resources such as JDBC Provider, Data Sources and Connection Pooling in order to connect to Oracle, DB2 databases.
- Successful implementations of Workload Management (WLM) using clustering techniques including Horizontal and Vertical Clustering for failover.
- Experienced in SSL certification creation and renewal for both application server and webserver.
- Involving Service level management process such as Incidents and Implementing Change Requests and Request Managements
- Created new Virtual Hosts, host aliases and done the generation, propagation of plug-in.
- Experienced in applying Fix Packs & Refresh Packs for Web Sphere application server.
- Monitoring server health and application health.
- Experienced in Configuring and enabling the Global Security System WAS Administration for console users and console Groups.
- Troubleshoot L1/L2 issues related to WebSphere architecture and applications in conjunction with helpdesk, development team, networking team, and vendor.

Honda, North America

- Role: DevOps Engineer -AWS Cloud & Middleware Administration
- Environment: Amazon web services, WebSphere Application Server 8.5, JBOSS EAP 7.0
- CI/CD tools: Jenkins, SVN, Apache Archiva repository, SonarQube
- OS: AIX, Linux

US Based Consulting Company

- Role : Cloud Infrastructure Specialist
- Cloud: AWS
- Environment : EC2, ELB, AMI's, VPC, S3
- OS : LinuxTeam Size : 6

Godrej

- Role : Infrastructure Specialist
- Environment: WAS 8.5, IHS 8.5, IBM DB2, LINUX, MQ

IBM Internal (Application Innovation & Cloud Services)

- Role: WebSphere Administrator
- Client : IBM Internal (Application Innovation & Cloud Services)
- Project : IBM Control Desk(MAXIMO TICKETING TOOL)
- Platform : AIX, Linux, DB2
- Technologies: WebSphere Application Server 8.5, IHS 8.5. TDS 6.3, Edge Load Balancer 8.5
- · Team Size: 6

- Worked closely with DevOps Architects to analyze, review and finalize the design on tools Implementation
- Setting up AWS infra as per there requirement, Plot the right services from the infra, End to End Implementation of the Solution
- Deploying new Ec2 Instances
- Created environments using VPC (VPC Peering), EC2, ELB, S3(Versioning)
- · Installing Java, JBoss in EC2 machines.
- Creating snapshots and AMIs of the EC2 instances for backup and creating clone instances
- Setting up and maintaining Dev, QA, Stage and Production environments
- Installing and configuring a complete WebSphere commerce environment including WebSphere Application Server, WebSphere Commerce Server, DB2, IBM HTTP server, MQ.
- Applying fix packs and feature packs on WebSphere application server and WebSphere Commerce server and enabled various feature pack features.
- · Enabling security using SSL and configuring LDAP
- Installation and configuration of WebSphere Edge Load Balancer.
- Installation and configuration of Tivoli Directory Server (LDAP) and setting up peer to peer replication.
- Installed and Configured Jenkins to use as a Continuous integration tool for automation of daily process
- · Built scripts using maven build tools using Jenkins
 - Installation and Configuration of WebSphere Application Server
 - Installed IHS Server on different nodes and configured them by generating the plug-in.
 - Experienced in Setting up of Nodes, Data Sources, including planning installation and configuration of WebSphere Application Server.
 - Created multiple Profiles on WebSphere Application server 7.x.8.x
 - Hands on experience in deployment of J2EE applications on WebSphere Application Servers 7.x.8.x
 - Involved in Configuring WebSphere resources such as JDBC Provider, Data Sources and Connection Pooling in order to connect to Oracle, DB2 databases.
 - Successful implementations of Workload Management (WLM) using clustering techniques including Horizontal and Vertical Clustering for failover.
 - Experienced in SSL certification creation and renewal for both application server and webserver.
 - Involving Service level management process such as Incidents and Implementing Change Requests and Request Managements
 - Created new Virtual Hosts, host aliases and done the generation, propagation of plug-in.
 - Experienced in applying Fix Packs & Refresh Packs for Web Sphere application server.
 - Monitoring server health and application health.
 - Experienced in Configuring and enabling the Global Security System WAS Administration for console users and console Groups.
 - Troubleshoot L1/L2 issues related to WebSphere architecture and applications in conjunction with helpdesk, development team, networking team, and vendor.